Guide to the Joseph W. Angell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Joseph Warner Angell papers
1937-1989
MS 1615
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The Joseph W. Angell Papers trace the acquisition of the Thomas Mann Collection for the Yale University Library in 1938 and the preparation of the 1950 exhibit to commemorate the seventy-fifth anniversary of Mann's birth. The papers also document the role of Joseph W. Angell as curator of the Thomas Mann Collection from 1948-1963.
Angell, Joseph Warner, 1908-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were the gift of Mrs. Joseph W. Angell in 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph W. Angell papers consist of correspondence, financial and legal papers, writings, and printed material which trace the acquisition of the Thomas Mann Collection for the Yale University Library in 1938 and the preparation of the 1950 exhibit to commemorate the seventy-fifth anniversary of Mann's birth. The papers also document the role of Joseph W. Angell as curator of the Thomas Mann Collection.
Biographical / Historical
Joseph Warner Angell, Jr. received his B.A. from the College of Wooster in 1930, and his M.A. from the University of Oregon in 1934. At Yale University, Angell was a reader in English from 1936-1939, an assistant professor during the summer of 1947, and curator of the Thomas Mann Collection from 1948-1963.
German literature; Angell, Joseph Warner, 1908-; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955; Yale University. Library
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938, undated
    - Altschul, Frank, 1937-1938, 1945, 1953-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B -H, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bürgin, Hans, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Feininger, Lyonel: bookplates for Thomas Mann Collection, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Herz, Ida, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Herz, Ida, 1950-1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - L -W, 1937-1939, 1046-1954, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Landis, Marshall David, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1937-1939, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lowe-Porter, Helen, 1937-1938, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mann, Katja (Mrs. Thomas Mann), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Seymour, Charles, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - White, James F.: transcriptions, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Yale University Library, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Yale University Library, 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Yale University Library, 1951-1952, 1980-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Financial and legal papers, 1937-1938, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Invitations, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1938, 1950, 1955, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Printed material, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Thomas Mann Collection at Yale
    - Address on dedication of the Thomas Mann Library at Yale University, [1938] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Yale University Library Gazette: "The Thomas Mann Collection," 1938; "The 1950 Thomas Mann Exhibition," 1951 Apr; with accompanying correspondence (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Thomas Mann in der Yale Universität, von Egon Vietta, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)